grid.org 2019-07-14

# Univa Corporation- Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

Univa is committed to respecting and protecting your right to privacy and we take your privacy seriously. We have a strictly enforced privacy policy and will keep your personal information secure. To communicate this, we have created this privacy policy to disclose and describe our information gathering and dissemination practices for our online communications.

### Collection of Your Personal Information

Most pages on this site can be viewed without providing any information about yourself. However, for some content we will request information that makes you personally identifiable.

  * • Your personal information is collected for internal use by Univa for site traffic analysis, response to requests and occasional marketing communications.
  * • All personal information submitted to Univa is done so voluntarily and with your consent.
  * • We pledge to hold all information you provide to us in absolute privacy.
  * • We will never sell or rent your name or personal information to any third party without your express permission.
  * • Only authorized employees may access your information.

### Subscription Status

We will occasionally send out information on our solutions, announcements and special offers. If you no longer wish to receive such communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by emailing us at [info@univa.com](mailto:info@univa.com).

### Changes to This Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. Univa reserves the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently.

### Enforcement of This Privacy Policy and Contact Information

The Univa web site contains links to other web sites, this privacy statement applies only to the Univa web site. Please review the privacy statement of any site before submitting your personally identifiable information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding our policy, or if you want to request the individual information Univa has collected about you via the Internet, contact us at [info@univa.com](mailto:info@univa.com).

### **For our European visitors**

Univa Corporation ( **Univa/we/us/our** ) is the data controller for any personal data collected via this website. We are committed to respecting and protecting your right to privacy and we take your privacy seriously. We have created this privacy policy to disclose and describe how we process personal data. 

The Univa website contains links to other websites. This privacy statement applies to Univa website only. Please review the privacy statement of our site before submitting your personal data.

### Collection of Your Personal Data

We collect personal data when you use our services, including using our website or corresponding with us. This includes:

  * • **Contact details** \- first and last name, e-mail address, company name, phone number, mailing address, country, states
  * • **Requests, feedback, sign-up information** \- all information your provide to us when contacting us via our website contact form, e-mail, telephone or other means of contact, including the name of the company or organization you work for, the country you are located in, the time and date you would like to attend our event or training; 
  * • **Application data** \- all information you provide to us when applying for a position with Univa; and
  * • **Technical information** \- IP address, referring URL, the pages that you visited on our website, the type and version of browser, operating system, demographics, the date and duration of the visit, and any other information captured by Google Analytics. 

### How Do We Use Your Personal Data?

We use your personal data for the following purposes:

  * • **To create a contract with you, or take steps linked to a contract with you**. This is relevant when you register for training or apply for a position with Univa and includes:
    * • providing services requested by you;
    * • processing payments;
    * • communicating with you; and
    * • assessing your suitability for the position you have applied to.

If the personal data we request is not provided, we may not be able to enter into or comply with a contract or our local legal obligations set hereafter.

  * • **In our legitimate interests regarding the conduct of our business, in particular:**
    * • ensuring customer satisfaction - we provide technical support and investigate and process any complaints about our website or our services, and to maintain appropriate records for internal administrative purposes.
    * • to protect our IT systems - monitor, test and control the performance and security of our systems, networks, processes and premises to prevent and detect interference and protect our business.
    * • developing and marketing services - to understand you and your company better as a customer by analyzing personal data you provide to us or which we learn through your interactions with us; and for monitoring the use of our website and apps in order to improve their performance and optimize our media spend.
    * • legal and regulatory purposes - in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory and investigative purposes as necessary (including disclosure of personal data in connection with claims, legal process or litigation).
  * • **Where you give us consent:**
    * • we will send you emails, texts and push notifications (including newsletters) in relation to services provided by us, or by our named affiliates and carefully selected partners; 
    * • we also share some of your personal data with marketing service and ad technology providers and digital marketing networks, such as Google to present advertisements that might be of interest to you. 
    * • when you visit our website, we place cookies and use similar technologies on your computer, mobile or other device and we use such technologies including pixel tags and web beacons in marketing emails and communications (see below for details on any cookies we use); and 
    * • on other occasions where we ask you for consent, we will use the personal data for the purpose which we explain at that time.

You have the right to withdraw consent at any time.

  * • **For purposes which are required by law:**
    * • in response to requests by government, law enforcement authorities or court orders.

### How Long Do We Retain Your Personal Data?

We delete personal data which we process based on your consent, for example in connection you're your subscription to newsletters, once you withdraw your consent.

We will not retain or use your personal data longer than necessary for the purposes outlined in this privacy policy. As an exception, we will not delete your personal data where we still have a legitimate interest to use your personal data. For example, we may still retain your personal data to resolve disputes, or comply with legal requirements. 

### With whom do we share your personal data?

We disclose or transfer personal data to other parties as follows:

    * • with other legal entities of the Univa Group, i.e. Univa Corporation and Univa Canada, if this is necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy policy, for example if your request concerns another company of the Univa Group, or to the extent this is necessary for internal administrative purposes;
    * • to third party service providers that perform processing operations on our behalf in relation to the website and the purposes set out in this privacy policy (for example, website hosting and technical support, marketing email service providers, online chat, data analysts website developers);
    * • if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with a legal obligation, or in order to enforce, defend or protect our rights and intellectual properties;
    * • to government authorities, and to other third parties when compelled to do so by government and law enforcement authorities, or otherwise as required or permitted by law, including but not limited to responses to court orders.

We process or transfer your personal data processed under this privacy policy outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ), for example where we transfer personal data to other companies of the Univa Group in the United States of America or Canada. We have implemented standard contractual clauses governing the transfer of your personal data outside the EEA. Please contact us at privacy@univa.com if you would like to obtain a copy of the standard contractual clauses.

### Cookies 

We use third party cookies to make our websites (including our mobile sites) work better. Cookies are small text files saved on your computer, smartphone or any other IT device when you visit our website. Cookies allow for recognition of your IP address and for collection of information about the pages you visit and which features you use. You can disable cookies by changing your browser settings. However, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information on our behalf for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for us and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage to the website provider. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.

Please note that we have extended the program code of Google Analytics to include the function "gat._anonymizeip(), so that Google will truncate/anonymise the last octet of the IP address for Member States of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to and shortened by Google servers in the USA. 

You can prevent Google's collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under the following link (https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de). 

Further information on Google Analytics can be found under  
https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html and   
https://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.

### Your rights

Wherever we rely on your consent, you will always be able to withdraw that consent. You have an absolute right to opt-out of direct marketing, and any profiling we carry out for direct marketing, at any time. You can do this by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link located in the footer of every marketing email or text.

In addition, you have the following rights:

    * • You have the right to know whether or not we process your personal data and to access that personal data.
    * • You have the right to update, correct and complete any personal data we hold about you which is inaccurate or incomplete.
    * • You have the right to obtain the personal data you provide to us for a contract or with your consent in a commonly used, structured, and machine-readable format, and to ask us to share (port) this personal data to another controller.
    * • You have the right to ask that we erase or restrict (stop active) processing of your personal data.
    * • In addition, you can object to the processing where the lawful basis is our legitimate interests, unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing.

These rights may be limited, for example if fulfilling your request would reveal personal data about another person or you ask us to erase personal data which we are required by law to keep. Where you object to us processing personal data we may have a compelling justification for processing it. We will inform you of relevant exemptions we rely upon when responding to any request you make.

To exercise any of these rights, you can get in touch with us at privacy@univa.com We hope that we can satisfy queries you may have about the way we process your personal data. However, if you have unresolved concerns you also have the right to complain to any data protection authority. 

### Contact

If you have questions or concerns regarding our privacy policy, or if you want to assert your data subject rights described above, contact us at privacy@univa.com or 2300 N. Barrington Road, Suite 400, Hoffman Estates, IL 60169, USA to the attention of the Data Protection Officer
